Oleksandr Fialko, Ph.D

021 293 58 39 oleksandrfialko@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/fialko http://oleksandrfialko.com

I am looking forward to extend my passion in problem solving and scientific expertise into datacentered industrial research. During my academic career I learned how to get the most of the data and make it to tell its story. I truly believe my research skills and experience will be beneficial to any organisation operating data.

Summary of skills

Core skills

I come from the discipline in which success depends on

- Strong mathematical background
- Numerical analysis
- Creativity
- Quick grasping the most advanced abstract ideas
- Thinking about the big picture
- Keeping an eye on details/order/quality
- Meeting tight deadlines

Strong analytical and problem solving skills:

I have written more than 20 papers in reputable physics journals. 4 papers were published in Physical Review Letters, the world's premier physics letter journal.

Determination, persistence and goal orientation:

I won a Fast-Start Marsden fund, which is one of the most prestigious funding for young researchers in New Zealand, with a success rate of less than 10%.

Solid programming skills:

Throughout different stages of my career I used extensively

- Python (Numpy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-learn)
- MATLAB
- Fortran

I am passionate about learning new programming skills. I have learned outside of work

- Machine learning models, SQL, R, C
- Basics of Web Development, cf. http://oleksandrfialko.com

Working experience in

Microsoft Windows, Linux, Mac OS X

Professional Experience

2013 - present, **Researcher at INMS**, Massey University, Auckland.

The Fast-Start Marsden fund gave me the opportunity to pursue my own research.

- Proposed an *isolated* quantum heat engine and did extensive numerical and theoretical research on its functionality. This project brought a *new concept* into the field.
- Invited to present my work at 4 international conferences.
- Awarded the status of Associate Investigator in the Dodd-Walls Centre for Photonic and Quantum Technologies.
- Received Dodd-Walls Centre New Ideas Research fund. Amount NZ \$25,000.
- Supervised a Ph.D student. Published 2 joint papers.
- Coordinated and conducted the course "Nonlinear Physics and Chaos".

2010 - 2013, Postdoctoral Fellow at CTCP, Massey University, Auckland.

I was hired to work on a Marsden Funded project at Massey.

- Proposed a scheme to simulate the early stages of the Universe with atoms in a lab. This project is a first in its nature and opens up a new field of research.
- Received AU \$5000 travel fund to visit the Swinburne University, Melbourne, Australia. I
 was a principal investigator of a research project.
- Supervised several internship students.
- Conducted seminars and labs on various aspects of physics to Massey students.

2005 - 2010, **Research Assistant & Ph.D**, University of Augsburg (Germany)

I was invited to pursue a Ph.D in theoretical physics and was hired as a research assistant.

- I was awarded a Ph.D with "great honor".
- Supervised a Masters student. Published 1 joint paper.
- Taught various undergraduate courses including examination preparation and marking.
- Received €6000 DAAD travel fund to visit the Institute of Physics, USP, Sao Paulo, Brazil for the period of 4 months. I was a principal investigator of a research project.

Education

- Certificate in "SQL Server Implementation and Support" (Transact SQL, Administering Microsoft SQL Server, Implementing SQL data warehousing), AMES I.T., New Zealand (March 2016).
- Doctor of Natural Sciences (with great honor), University of Augsburg, Germany (June 2010)
- Master in Physics (with honor),
 Kiev National University, Ukraine (June 2005)
- Bachelor in Physics (with honor),
 Kiev National University, Ukraine (June 2004).

Certified Courses

- "Machine learning" by Stanford University on Coursera (final grade 97.3%)
- "Programming in R for Data Science" by Microsoft on EDX (final grade 99%)